Our families hundreds of years ago
didn't have a last name. Why did we not
have a last name? Because we couldn't
have an identity because we were
someone's slave. We're living in an age
where the digital companies, the web two
companies, Facebook, Amazon, Zulkai, are
basically the biggest rent seekers in
the world. They become the landlords.
This is a landlord environment. If you
have a million followers on Instagram,
it's not yours. You actually become a
slave to Instagram. How many musicians
make money actually streaming on
Spotify? Zero. You care about the
virtual reputation. That status is
valuable. Mhm.
>> And so if that's true, then why don't
you get to own it? If you own your data,
if you own your identity, if you own
your digital property rights, all the
value flows to you.
>> Obviously, Facebook, Instagram, they
don't want you to.
>> This is happening right now.
>> What a pleasure to have Yatsu with us.
He is the co-founder and executive
chairman of Animoka Brands. He is the
superstar. as we walk to this room. He's
been stopped by, I think, a thousand
people. Right. Finally, you're here.
>> Thank you. No, I'm not a superstar, but
much appreciated. Thank you.
>> I watch a lot of your interviews, and
one thing you mention over and over
again is the importance of property
rights.
>> Um, can you tell us more what you mean
by that?
>> Well, generally the foundation of
capitalism can only work with property
rights. If you don't have ownership of
something, then you don't have the
freedom to do things with it. Mhm.
>> And so owning something means that you
have the freedom to transact, to do
stuff, and nobody else can tell you what
to do with it. It's the ultimate form of
freedom. And when I talk about property
rights, not just digital property
rights, I talk about the ultimate form
of ownership, which is ownership in
yourself. Now, that sounds a little bit
philosophical, but you own a name. Yes.
>> And that name is who you are, and it's
your identity.
>> Our families hundreds of years ago
didn't have a last name. Why did we not
have a last name? because we didn't have
an identity because we were someone's
slave. We were the property of someone
else.
>> I didn't know that.
>> I mean, you know, many of our last names
are based on the district we come from,
the village we're in, or maybe our
profession, right? Because we didn't
have a name. We had to basically adopt
the name of the area eventually when we
had the freedom to do so and said,
"Okay, I come from the city, so I'll be
named after the city.
>> I live next to this lake, so I'll be
named after this lake." And what happens
when you have a name, you have an
identity. Mhm.
>> And when you have an identity, you own
your own property. You own yourself.
That's the beginning.
>> The beginning of that freedom. I know it
sounds like, you know, in a world in a
world where most people seem free and
have the freedom, they take it for
granted. That's the other thing. Like we
take our democracies for granted. We
don't always go to vote. But that's a
freedom we fought for. Just how
thousands of years ago we fought for our
freedom to have our own name.
Raid: Shadow Legends.
QR
iPad.
Okay.
But it could be my freedom to not vote.
>> That's correct. And that is uh and and I
think this is the thing. You have the
freedom to do so as long as you don't
hurt someone else. And that's fine.
>> But I think the point is that respecting
how you got that freedom
>> is you know an important aspect around
that right so and I think this is why
property rights is so important because
most people will agree that you should
own your own things.
>> You shouldn't give it to someone else.
And the dangerous arguments that
happened were, you know, I grew up in
Europe during the time when we had still
east and west western Europe and in a
very super socialist environment like a
like a like a like true communism. Not
that we see that anymore today in this
construct. You don't own any property.
And the idea of not owning property was
meant to say we can all be equal. We
don't have to worry about this house
that house you live in. But that's not
what makes us human, right? We are
different. Every person is different.
And we want to identify in different
ways and we express ourselves in the
kinds of property that we have.
>> And how does that translate to the
digital world?
>> Well, the digital world is relevant here
because where do we spend most of our
time?
>> Online.
>> Online. Digital. We spend, you know,
depending where 8 to 10 hours a day
online. So our value system is entirely
online. How many people care more about
how many followers they have on
Instagram, how many likes they get. M
>> I mean how many people pay, you know,
like I don't know about you, but I do
know a lot of people who are younger
than me who spend a lot of time
preparing their photos and expressing
themselves in social media.
>> That's effort and time that they don't
that they're giving away freely.
>> But it's important because that
recognition,
>> that reputation is more important than
their physical one. in. You know, I grew
up in a time where it was important
which restaurants you went to, which
clubs you were seeing, what newspapers
were writing about you. Now, we care
about what influencer talks about you,
how many likes you have on Instagram,
how many followers do you have, you
know, how much credit you have in a
game, you care about the virtual
reputation. That status is valuable.
>> And so, if that's true, then why don't
you get to own it? At least in the
physical world, you own your reputation.
But in the digital world, if you have a
million followers on Instagram, it's not
yours. You actually become a slave to
Instagram. Because what happens is that
if Instagram says, "If you don't do what
I tell you to do, I'm going to delete
your account." Likely likelihood is that
you will comply instead of saying,
"Well, I can go somewhere else cuz guess
what? You can't."
>> Yeah.
>> And that's why digital property rights
is the ultimate form of that because now
I own this and I can take it somewhere
else. And the token infrastructure
allows you to do that. So I can
basically now take my assets elsewhere
just how I can take my Bitcoin and it's
mine. Nobody else can take that away. My
digital reputation in the form of my
NFTts or my assets or my tokens I can
actually transfer freely and people can
follow that and give me credit for that.
You know like when you think about
digital reputation why can I not take my
Uber rating and my Amazon rating to
somewhere else?
>> I don't know.
>> Well because they don't want you to
because obviously they want you to stay
in Amazon. So if I wanted to open a new
account on eBay or somewhere else, I
have to start all over again. That
switching cost is high. But it was you
who built up the effort. You built a
network. It is your customers. And yet
actually you built their customers,
right?
>> We're living in an age where the digital
companies, the web two companies,
Facebook, Amazon, those guys are
basically the biggest rent seekers in
the world. They've become the landlords.
>> This is this is a landlord environment
in Hong Kong. And I'm sure maybe Taipei
has a similar issue. You when you make a
restaurant,
>> if you don't own the property of your
>> you will keep buying paying higher rent,
higher rent, higher rent until
eventually
>> you basically have nothing and the
landlord gets everything. And guess
what? You just made the value of the
land valuable because people go there
for attention and then they rent it to
some other restaurant for higher rent
and you're out of business because you
don't own that land.
>> That's digital land.
>> Basically, digital property is the
version of that. Do you want to keep
paying rent to Instagram? Now, you might
say it's free, but the reality is that
the data you're generating, they make
money off you. They make money off in
the billions. In fact, trillion dollar
market caps come from that.
>> The advertising industry u is about $1.1
trillion a year, of which 70 to 80% is
owned by Apple, Facebook, Google, those
guys, they make all that value. How do
they make it?
>> Because of you. You're spending time.
Who's bringing in customers? You.
Because you're advertising and promoting
and telling your friends about it. Who
spends hours trying to figure out how to
make the photo attractive so they can
get more likes so they can get more
advertising? You, right? And how much do
you get paid? There's a very small
percentage, you know, like the Taylor
Swifts or the Mr. Beasts of the world
that can that can make money from this,
but the vast majority does not. And this
is not just for social media. It's
music. How many musicians make money
actually streaming on Spotify? Zero.
>> Really?
>> No. They make they make piddles. They
use Spotify basically as a way to
promote themselves and they make money
from gigs and performances. Right.
Right? And so you have 70 to 80 year old
performers that could be streamed
billions of times and they still do
shows because that's how they pay their
bills, right? That type of stuff because
they don't have property ownership in in
in the digital reality. So this is this
is why digital property rights is so
fundamentally important.
>> Okay, I understand that it is important.
But in real life, what would it look
like? Let's say now people care about
this topic enough to make a change. Do
we switch platforms or like because
obviously Facebook, Instagram, they
don't want you to.
>> Well, the platform's already here. It's
called blockchain.
>> If you basically if you basically build
out on blockchain,
>> it may appear that you have less
customers because the ecosystem is
smaller.
>> However, you make much more money per
user.
>> So, there there's a concept in 2008
published by Kevin Kelly. It's called a
thousand true fans. And the idea back
then was that you get a thousand true
fans, you'll be fine
>> because they will pay you $100 for
whatever it is that you want, right? And
you see this in restaurants and
artifacts and things like Etsy and so
on. You see those thousand crew fans.
>> Well, of course, now the value has to be
higher. But what's a,000 crew fans in
crypto? You see them in NFTs and token
holders and they spend a lot more than
$100. You can build bigger business from
them. So you don't need 10 million
customers. You just need thousands,
maybe tens of thousands of very
concentrated users and you will
basically have a sort of insured revenue
stream and then build and expand from
that base. The problem is that whether
on Spotify or Instagram, the people who
follow you, you don't know how many of
them are following you just because
they're being polite or because they're
interested, but are they your true fan?
No, they're not your true fan. How do I
know that you're a true fan? I need to
know who's the person who interacts with
my post 10 times a day or 100 times a
day. I need to know the one who's
thinking about my content. Who cares
about what I do? That's my thousand true
fans.
>> But we can'tice unless you own the data.
How do you own the data on chain? One
way to prove the data is what NFTs do
you have? How much money have you
invested? That's the first way in which
you can measure that. But it's not the
only way, right? How many things have
you transacted? How many hours have you
played? You don't know that, but you
know that basically on blockchain
because it's all on chain. And so now
you create a market from that. Your data
becomes the market. And that only
doesn't and it means you as an end user
by the way get rewarded too because now
I can say oh I go to your podcast and I
listen to your content so many hours.
What if I make content that's similar a
different twist but now I can reach you
directly because I know that you would
appreciate this stuff. So the whole
advertising customer segmentation market
changes. So I I mentioned about the
trillion dollars of advertising.
>> So what's the advertising efficiency
rate on Facebook?
>> I have no idea.
>> Less than 10%.
So I mean that's scattershot. You're
basically going out and you know
spending a million dollars
>> and really only 100,000 reaches the
customer and in many cases much less
than that.
>> Mhm.
>> So that's basically huge wasted effort.
Right now if you can be more direct and
targeted because you have the open data
then what happens is that you spend more
efficient dollars in advertising which
means more money is captured in the
value chain between the businesses and
the end user. That's why airdrops work
because I give people an airdrop and if
the airdrop is used owned by a user and
he uses an ecosystem is much more likely
to spend in the ecosystem whether it's a
game or blockchain rather than just
cashing out. Um which is basically
what's happening uh with web two
companies like in the gaming industry we
spend $und00 billion a year advertising
games.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh the average cost per paying customer
is about $80 to $85 to bring in to
become a paying customer. Which means
unless your game makes more than $85 per
user, you're toast.
Now, of the billions of dollars that
Facebook, Google, Apple make advertising
your game, not to mention 30% cut they
take off the revenue share, how much do
they reinvest back in the gaming
ecosystem?
>> Zero.
>> That's right.
>> Cuz I've watched your interviews.
>> Thank you. But the point is that is it's
zero. Right now, if a portion of that
value goes to the gamer or all of the
value goes to the gamer, the chances of
him spending in your game is much
higher. And even if he doesn't spend it
in your game, he might spend it in
another game. And so it generally
benefits the ecosystem as a whole.
Right? So so this is the whole point
about ownership. If you own your data,
if you own your identity, if you own
your digital property rights, all the
value flows to you. Those trillions of
dollars of value they generated should
be distributed and owned by the end
users that provided that value in the
first place. That's why it's so
important. And blockchain is the
mechanism to do that. And so it's not
about, you know, having 10 million
users.
>> It's about having true fans. and they
could be millions, but if you know who
your thousand true fans are, you've got
your foundation for your business. And
that's what really every creator, every
developer, every small shop owner really
wants to have.
>> So in 10 years, when you look at social
media, for example, are we talking about
thousands of different platforms all
with a smaller fan base or what does it
look like? Like in in crypto, we
understand this.
>> I think the way you can think of it is
how many tokens are there today and how
many tokens will there be in the future.
So in other words, so right now we have
millions and millions of tokens and
there will be billions of tokens and the
mental model I see of it is in forms of
attention is a websites. So if you
remember in the you might be too young
to know this but in the '90s uh we used
to have this thing called a website a
normal website and that was the way that
we would build attention and today u you
know we have actually billions of
websites because they're now
encapsulated in the form of Tik Tok,
Instagram, Facebook. So you as an
individual probably have 10, 20, 30
websites, you know, with your business,
with your sort of presences.
>> Each of these are going to be tokens
>> because they're essentially ways in
which you can value the attention of
your network. They don't have to be
worth a a lot. But imagine if you could
consolidate all of the forms of your
websites to yourself based on your
business or your activity.
>> Well, that's one way in which you
capture the value because it's not
segregated. It's connected. And once it
becomes interoperable, you basically
have the benefit of that free trade of
that flow. Right? So that's the first
part. So you're going to have billions
of tokens. To me, this means that we're
going to have billions of tokens
distributed amongst the creators and the
users. You'll have a token, I'll have a
token. Um my daughter will have a token.
My friends will all have tokens. We may
never see the token directly, but we'll
be able to transact with them and
they'll be part of this money system and
the ecosystem if I want to do business
with you. And then what happens is that
you're going to have some of these
explode in terms of becoming much bigger
and then they become their own
platforms, right? You have big
companies, you have small companies. So
small companies will still have on the
back end their token infrastructure. And
to me, this is no different than what we
see with data centers and with, you
know, Amazon web services for instance.
99% of the world is just going to
outsource to Amazon web services. But if
you're big enough, you have your own
data center or you have your own web web
servers because you need that scale and
that's the functionality or that that
optimization. Right? To me, I see
exactly this the same framing. So,
there'll be people that have everyone
will have a token will be represented in
this way. Um whether they know it's a
token or not is almost secondary because
it could be abstracted.
>> Mhm. As in like how Okay. So, I have my
token, you have your token. How do we
interact?
>> Okay. So, the way that you might
interact um two ways and just the
beautiful thing about blockchain is that
third parties can come in and do the
interaction for you. So if you have a
token and I have a token and I'm using
Facebook as a platform to interact but I
don't like that or someone else goes you
know what Facebook's taking too much
money I'll make a platform to make allow
your interactions to interact better
with the other. That's actually where
this grows and property ownership the
beautiful thing about property ownership
is the unlimited composability that
happens. So the fact that we own
physical cars is a reason you have Uber,
Lift, tire companies, baby seat
companies, people who hire drivers,
people who basically, you know, create
sort of, you know, sound devices. Like
the industry of people building stuff
for people who own cars is bigger than
the people who are selling cars,
>> right? That's the opportunity. And so
that composability is what blockchain is
at its root. When you're building
something on blockchain, it's
composable. So, if you have a token, be
it an NFT or just a general token,
someone else can come in. I'm going to
interact with your token. I'm going to
build DeFi or I'm going to build a game
on top of it. I'm going to use it. Now,
he'll do it because he'll want access to
that customer base. You get benefit
because it ends up greasing your
ecosystem and growing it and there's
more utility and ultimately you're now
building relationships whether you like
it or not within your ecosystem. That's
the power. So, all transactions are
relational in a way, especially in Asia.
You know, often you start with money and
you can make friendships as well. That
happens as well. But the point is that
transactions are relational in in a
construct, but it's often onetoone. It's
hard to scale relations, right? What
social media companies have done is
they've abstracted relations and created
it on scale on mass, but they've made it
sort of commoditized,
>> meaning that your like and my like are
not differentiated. But that's not true,
right? You know if if if Elon Musk was
to follow me on X,
>> my value would be much higher than
100,000 random people as much as I might
like them right the value is different
right so we can't say that every like is
the same or every follow is the same
it's not true but they don't want you to
know that in blockchain you cannot
ascertain that and that means that I can
now create more relationship with
another by people who I'm not even
interacting with if we have a token
someone can build applications on top of
your ecosystem and build relations on
your behalf and benefit benefit from it
without me ever doing anything, right?
And and then next thing I know, I might
have a community that was built from
someone else. We all become almost like
our many states, our many nations that
we can build our communities from.
>> So, this is not just an idea. This is
happening, right?
>> This is happening right now.
>> Okay. How tell me the time horizon. How
many years until we see this happening?
>> Oh, I think it's going to be within the
next 10 years.
>> 10 years.
>> Yeah. That So, and the reason why I
think this is going to accelerate so
quickly is a couple things. One, the
advent of AI is going to accelerate
everything. So AI is going to be
transacting at light speed everywhere.
Um, we're all going to have multiple AI
agents doing stuff for us. What is the
native asset that they're going to be
trading on? It's going to be crypto.
They don't have bank accounts. They
can't do KYC, right? And they're going
to be doing this 24/7. So that's also
the reason we think of crypto as a
natural hedge uh towards AI. Like if you
can't invest in open AI, then maybe you
own Bitcoin. That's your hedge towards a
an AI future as an example, right? Um
but but that basically means that we're
going to have this proliferation of that
and this will happen very very quickly.
The second thing is all companies and
institutions are all going to tokenize.
This is something that was already
happening but was held back because the
US was so hostile before under the
previous administration with Trump
coming in and crypto becoming much more
bipartisan. This entire market is
blowing wide open because the whole
world now if they want to do business
with the US they need to be pro crypto.
So that's going to accelerate and it's
going to basically do what we saw with
the internet. The internet grew slowly
and then it exploded. Crypto grew slowly
and then it exploded too, you know, and
exactly what the internet did for
information, right? We're now having,
you know, um this, you know, value and
value creation at the speed of the
internet is what we're seeing with
blockchain. Um which before we had with
knowledge and information with the with
the advent of the internet.
>> I have so many other questions that I
would like to ask you, but I know you
have to go. Um please come back soon.
Let's do it virtually. I'd love to ask
you about GameFi and all that. You know,
you are the goat when it comes to
>> I will maybe maybe before I go, I'll
I'll give you my my my two cents on
GameFi.
>> So, first of all, onchain activity on
gaming um is the highest as in it's it's
it's it's higher than before.
>> Uh also, most of the onchain activity is
related to GameFi.
>> However, most of the activity that
happens in crypto today is trading, not
necessarily playing games. It's
happening in centralized exchanges. So
we have about a half a billion people
that own crypto now in different
exchanges somewhere around that number
right individual users but there's only
about 10% of them that are on chain
>> and so the reason we don't feel this
impact is because the people who own
your token and the people who play your
game are not necessarily the same
>> the ven diagram between the two are not
the same
>> but that number as more people go on
chain is changing this will have a big
impact on game fun. The second thing I
will say um and that's happening sooner.
Like we're very bullish on on on crypto
gaming next year. The reason why is GTA
>> and it's not because we think take 2 is
going to tokenize. It's going to be that
it's going to bring the emphasis back
into gaming. You need these triggers.
Like what created the big trigger on
gaming in the metaverse back in 21. It
was Facebook renaming itself to Meta.
What's the trigger we think that's going
to do that from a macro scale? It's
going to be GTA 6 because it's going to
be the biggest cultural event ever. It's
going to be in the gaming area. It's
going to drive more console sales. It's
going to increase prices of games, more
game revenue. Uh, and then more
importantly, GTA 6 has the ability to
run your own RP servers, role-play
servers. So, basically means it's a
decentralized ecosystem. And I'm very
certain that people are going to start
running crypto on these RP servers and
they're going to grow those ecosystems.
And so, it's going to be a pretty
exciting time, I think, next year.
>> Can we have you on next year then?
>> Oh, you can have me on before that, of
course. Be a pleasure. Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. Thank you. Such a
great insight. Thank you very much.
Thank you.